# Sreenivas Shikar R

Bengaluru, Karnataka | shikarraju7890@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/srini94 | +91 7019916858 | https://srini-portfolio.tech/

#### PROFILE SUMMARY

Software developer with 5 Years 11 Months Experience expertise on devops and web Development. Currently seeking a challenging role within a respected organization, aiming to apply both my technical and management skills to advance product development and foster personal growth

### **SKILLS**

DevOps | Docker hub | Harbor | CI/CD | GitHub Actions | git | Cloud | Jenkins | AWS | Ansible | Sonarqube |
Automation | API | Terraform | Python | Groovy | MySQL | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap 4 | Backend Development | Web
Development | FastAPI | Bash | shell Script | Linux | Project Management | Communication | Leadership | Time
Management | Adaptability | Problem-Solving | Teamwork | Creativity | Kubernetes |

## **TOOLS USED**

Monitoring | ElasticSearch | kibana | APM | Grafana | Prometheus | Nagois | Apache Airflow | Jira | Confluence | MySQL Work Bench | Postman | Jenkins | git | MS Teams | MS Outlook | VS Code

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

SDE II – Devops

May 2021 – April 2024

Rakuten | Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Developed the Jenkins Deployment pipelines, resulting in a remarkable **reduction of 80% deployment time**.
- Delivered Pipelines using jenkins ci/cd for Automated integration testing that uses Selenium to perform UI Testing, **effectively saving over 4 hours of manual testing time** in each sprint.
- Implemented APM,ELK,GRAFANA,PROMETHEUS into PMO projects thus helping developers to recognize the root cause in application performance and monitoring.
- Actively engaged with both DEV and QA team, providing technical guidance and support to make sure the sprint releases happen as per scheduled.
- Actively engaged in role of development primarily on backend technologies to create API and have worked on multiple web development projects.
- Developed backend API's in co-ordination with frontend developers using Python.

Web Developer July 2018 - June 2019

Rolling Stone Solutions Pvt Ltd | Bengaluru, Karnataka

• Developed Websites and Landing Pages, in coordination with marketing team successfully streamlined operations and achieved more leads.

- Executed strategies that Involved in google and Facebook marketing campaigns to **increase sales of our services by 50%.**
- Developed jenkins Pipeline system to make sure smooth deployments.

Web Developer Oct 2016 - June 2018

Plassa Enterprises | Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Developed Websites for a product called jowist (Joy-With-Study).
- Day to day activities involved in coordination with UX designer and CxO to meet the sprint targets.

#### **PROJECTS**

## Projects Worked(7) :: RCMS ,ET, Space-Studio, E-sign, RDF, PTT, SIIMS

- Designed and Developed web applications on cloud (RIAAS/ONE CLOUD/AWS) and integrated Docker
   Swarm orchestration / Kubernetes K8s for managing cluster of containers.
- Developed API's as required for front end engineers using python.
- Developed pipeline for Unit Testing in collaboration with QA team.
- Executed the Containerization of the application using Docker and established a CICD pipeline to build and push a new image every time the application is modified.
- Implemented Role Based access to the project team members who used to perform the deploy actions.
- Leveraged GitHub Actions to automate syncing code when code changes are made using web hook.
- Integrated Teams notification on every successful deployment.
- Integrated Monitoring tools like APM, ELK, Grafana, Prometheus.
- Implemented a prod monitor suite that runs in Jenkins to keep Monitoring of application.
- Achieved the tasks in collaboration with front end engineers as a role of backend developer successfully.

# **Rakuten Tech Conference – AI-Nization**

- Executed End to End development of the website in collaboration with UX Designers and Cxo's and successfully launched with **Zero QA issues**.
- https://tech.rakuten.co.jp/

# Detailed Explanation of projects with tech stacks and tools used

- Please visit the below link to get detailed tech stacks, tools, language used in various projects.
- https://srini-portfolio.tech/

# **EDUCATION**

# **BE** in Electronics and Communication Engineering ECE)

Jul 2012 - Aug 2016

BMS Institute of Technology & Management (Bengaluru)